Zachary Riesland

Creedmoor, NC zack.riesland@gmail.com www.ZackRiesland.com

PROFILE

Java Developer. .NET/C# Developer. Code ninja.

8 years of professional experience in software design and development using Java, C#, C++, VB, SQL 4 years of professional experience in freelance website design and development using WordPress, HTML, Javascript, JQUERY, PHP, and MySQL.

I am the walking definition of "works hard - gets things done."

I recognize that the quality of my work is a reflection of who I am, so I always give 110%. I have been quickly and consistently promoted throughout my professional career, with a consistent record of excellence. I guarantee that if you give me a chance, I'll blow you away.

EDUCATION

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

- •Graduated Summa Cum Laude in University Honors AND University Scholars Programs; GPA: 3.99
- •Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; May, 2005

J.F. Webb High School, Oxford, NC

- •Graduated 3rd in class
- •Achieved 1550 SAT score

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Gilbarco Veeder-Root; Greensboro/Durham, NC 2008-Present

Full-time software developer/designer. Design and implement software to enhance a series of products that run at almost 30,000 sites across the country and process almost half a billion dollars every day. Primary technologies are Java, .NET/C#, XML, JAXB, MSSQL Server, VB6. Design is part service-oriented. Includes complicated test and debug scenarios using multiple computers, virtual machines, and emulators. Part of a large team that uses a strict SCRUM approach, but often work remotely, which requires intense discipline and crisp communication. Contact me for more details.

Software Engineer/Tech Team Lead, Intelligent Information Systems; Durham, NC 2006-2008

Full-time software developer/designer and technical team lead. Three major projects, including smart client and web client with major database back-ends under government contracts. Intense understanding of business use cases required. Small and large team dynamics, including remote development teams. Many different roles, including technical team lead. Technologies include .NET 1.1/2.0.3.0, C#, ASP, Visual Studio 2003/2005, Javascript, XML, NUnit, N-Coverage, FX-Cop, Codesmith and MyGeneration (dynamic code generation), CSLA, TestDriven.NET, MS Sequel Server 2003/2005, Oracle 9i/10g, ODP.NET, Infragistics, ASPose, MS Exchange API, Batch Programming

Missionary, Campus Crusade For Christ; Central Asia 2005-2006

English, computer skills, and programming teacher under an NGO. Lived among team of 7 for 11 months. Learned some language and some culture. Helped design and maintain the NGO website. Made friends, made disciples, learned a lot about what the Gospel means, who I am, and who I am not. Was kicked out will all foreigners before our stint was over.

Software Engineer, IBM; Raleigh, NC 2003-2005

Co-op and then part-time intern position at IBM's OTI-Labs in Raleigh. Primarily embedded programming of Java libraries for mobile phones and PDAs using Eclipse IDE. Experience included Java, ANT, C, JUnit, TCK, scripting (bash, batch, perl), Windows 2000/XP, Windows CE, Windows Mobile, Linux, Unix, QNX, QT, GTK, Eclipse, Bugzilla, VS 2003/2005, eVC++

SKILLS

Deep experience in Java, .NET/C#/VB, SQL, XML, code generation tools, test-driven development. Comfortable in group-oriented work, particularly using agile project management. Also comfortable working individually.

Additional experience in JSP, PHP, LISP, Assembler, Web Design, JUnit, TCK, Perl, Bash, Linux, Unix, QNX, Windows 2000/XP, Windows CE, Windows Mobile 2005, Wordpress, various CMS, Eclipse, Visual Studio, eVC++, Data Mining, e-Commerce, Mac OSX

Web Design:

I do freelance web design for an array of clients. I have several years of experience in HTML, CSS, PHP, ASP.NET, Javascript, XML, SQL, JQuery, JSON, Wordpress, and Google Maps API.

Visit www.ZackRiesland.com to see my web design portfolio.

HONORS/AWARDS

NCSU University Honors Program founding member and graduate; NCSU University Scholars Program; NCSU Order of Thirty and Three; Phi Kappa Phi; NCSU Benjamin Franklin Scholarship; James Johnston Scholarship

REFERENCES

Available upon request